+1(470)838-0620 • parthketandoshi@gmail.com • Atlanta, GA - 30338 • parthketandoshi.github.io linkedin.com/in/parthketandoshi • github.com/parthketandoshi • leetcode.com/parthketandoshi

SUMMARY

Full-stack Software Engineer with 3+ years of experience in development of Enterprise-grade Products with expertise in Angular and React. I have a passion for programming, a knack for problem solving and an aptitude for learning. I also have experience of working as a Freelance Graphic Designer which has helped me in developing a keen sense of understanding for Front-end UI/UX.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, C, Java, Python, SQL, JSON, jQuery, SASS Technology Stack: React, Redux, JSX, Angular 8+, RxJS, MongoDB, Node.js, NPM, Bootstrap, Spring Boot, Kafka, WCAG, NLP Tools: WordPress, Inkscape, AWS, Dialogflow, REST API, Postman, Firebase, Jenkins, Git, BitBucket, Jira, JUnit, Selenium

WORK EXPERIENCE

AVPS Technologies Inc

Alpharetta, GA

Full-stack Software Engineer, EdTech Product

May 2023 - Present

- Implemented React front-end components, Java microservices, MognoDB back-end and Kibana dashboards in the 2 platforms
- Refactored legacy code base ensuring adherence to software development standards improving performance and processes

Georgia State University

Atlanta, GA

Graduate Assistant, Computer Information Systems Department

August 2022 - July 2023

Developed professor's portfolio website and conducted research on advances in digital business transformation and RPA

Zycus Infotech Pvt Ltd, Enterprise SaaS Procurement Product Suite

Mumbai, India

Full-stack Software Engineer with Front-end Focus (Angular), UI Centre of Excellence

January 2021 - August 2022

- Collaborated with managers and teams from 20+ products, services, and applications to deliver 80+ business requirements
- Undertook development and enhancement of user stories and bug fixes across 2 core libraries, 1 core product and 1 platform
- Developed and enhanced 47 front-end components using Angular for the UI library and undertook POC tasks for the same
 Liaised with UI/UX design team as development SPOC to audit adherence of mockups to SLAs and WCAG A11Y standards
- Implemented the UI theme, 6 launch points and 10 manifestation areas for the app store platform and its integration in products
- Implemented 3 critical data dashboards get comprehensive and granular visibility of 16 products, services and CRMS
- Upgraded language management system platform and BFF from Java 8 to OpenJDK 11 and migrated public dependencies
- Automated icon code generation and publishing process eliminating 12 hours of manual effort and optimized performance
- Improved reliability, maintainability, scalability, and security achieving an overall rating of A across all products and applications
- Groomed 8 resources through knowledge sharing & knowledge transfer sessions and authored documentation on best practices

CampK12

Mumbai, India

App Development Instructor

April 2020 - May 2020

Taught android app development and AR/VR game development to 47 K-12 students with an aggregate rating of 4.76 on 5

Fube Technology

Malaysia (Remote)

Front-end Developer (Contract)

December 2018 - March 2019

Developed a social media platform and a video sharing web application using Firebase, Laravel, Bootstrap and MySQL

Trivia Softwares

Mumbai, India

Android and Python Application Developer

July 2018 - August 2018

Implemented a healthcare android app and a student database python GUI desktop application with Oracle server back-end

Toppr

Mumbai, India

WordPress Administrator and SEO Manager

February 2018 - July 2018

Developed and edited educational content, and maintained SEO on the EdTech platform while managing a team of freelancers

VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCES

Indian Society for Technical Education

Teach for India

Computer Society of India

TAPtheTECH

SELECTED PROJECTS

Angular Social Media Platform - Angular web application fetching data from APIs and displaying profiles of fictional users along with their details, posts, and images after logging in utilizing components from Angular Material design and hosted it using Firebase **Bridge Health Monitoring System** - A comprehensive IoT platform for monitoring structural health of bridges comprising embedded sensors, Python applications for Image & Audio processing, and a Progressive Web Application hosted using Firebase

EDUCATION

Georgia State University, J. Mack Robinson College of Business

Atlanta, GA

Master of Science, Computer Information Systems, GPA - 4.0

2023

University of Mumbai
Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Engineering, GPA - 3.0

Mumbai, India 2020

PUBLICATION

^{&#}x27;Survey on IoT based Bridge Health Monitoring Systems', IJRESM, ISSN-2581-5792, Impact Factor- 5.72, April 2020